# Eli Schwartz, PhD – Curriculum Vitae

me@eli-schwartz.com

+972-505-790959

Google Scholar

LinkedIn

I am an AI Research Scientist with 15 years of tech experience, holding a strong publication record in top-tier conferences such as NeurIPS, CVPR, AAAI, and ICCV. I am dedicated to performing research that has a significant, real-world impact and drives progress in practical applications. My primary research interests are in representation learning and vision and language foundation models.

### Education

### 2019-2023

## Ph.D. Electrical Engineering, Tel-Aviv University, Israel

- Advisors Prof. Raja Giryes (TAU) and Prof. Alex Bronstein (CS@Technion)
- Thesis "Adaptable Computer Vision Models for Shifting Data Distributions", Adapting Deep Learning models to new data distributions with limited data (Few-shot Learning; Domain Adaptation/Generalization; Anomaly Detection).

#### 2016-2018

# M.Sc. Electrical Engineering, Tel-Aviv University, Israel

- Advisors Prof. Raja Giryes (TAU) and Prof. Alex Bronstein (CS@Technion)
- Thesis "Learning an End-to-End Image Processing Pipeline". First to show learning of the entire camera's image processing pipeline in an end-to-end fashion.

#### 2007-2011 B.Sc. Electrical Engineering, Technion - Israel institute of technology

# **Employment**

# 2017-Present Research Scientist – IBM Research AI

- Published and productized research.
- Led a customer-facing project, collaborating closely with dev, UX, product, and CS.
- Achievements: 11 Papers; 6 Patents; 2 research projects delivered as products.

#### 2015-2017

## Co-founder & CTO – Inka Robotics

- Co-founded a startup focused on developing a vision-based autonomous tattooing robot.
- Spearheaded the technical team, overseeing the development of software and algorithms.
- Successfully transformed the concept into a working prototype, culminating in a tattoo on my own leg.

#### 2013-2016

#### Computer Vision Algorithm Developer - Microsoft

- Contributed to the HoloLens AR Glasses Project in its early days.
- Served as a member of an incubation team, rapidly developing PoCs for cutting-edge technologies.
- Specialized in developing computer vision algorithms, notably for depth cameras and gaze tracking.

#### 2011-2013

# ASIC Engineer – Qualcomm

Played a pivotal role as the Formal Verification Technical Lead

#### 2008-2011

#### ASIC Engineering Intern - IBM

Gained hands-on experience in ASIC formal and functional verification

#### **Awards**

- The Weinstein Research Institute for Signal Processing's Outstanding Paper Award, 2023
- IBM PhD Fellowship Award, 2021-2022
- IBM Research Accomplishment Award, 2020
- IBM Invention Plateau Award (for prolific inventors), 2020
- IMVC Best Student Paper, 2019
- Thomas Schwartz Award for outstanding projects (Senior Thesis), 2011

# Peer-reviewed papers

- S. Doveh, A. Arbelle, S. Harary, **E. Schwartz**, R. Herzig, R. Giryes, D. Kim, R. Feris, R. Panda, S. Ullman, L. Karlinsky, "*Teaching Structured Vision & Language Concepts to Vision & Language Models*", CVPR 2023 pdf
- D. Lang, **E. Schwartz**, C. Bercea, R. Giryes, J. Schnabel, "Multispectral 3D Masked Autoencoders for Anomaly Detection in Non-Contrast Enhanced Breast MRI", CAPTION Workshop MICCAI 2023 pdf
- **E. Schwartz**, R. Giryes and A. M. Bronstein, "*ISP Distillation*", IEEE Open Journal of Signal Processing 2022 pdf
- A. Alfassy\*, A. Arbelle\*, O. Halimi, S. Harary, R. Herzig, **E. Schwartz**, R. Panda, M. Dolfi, C. Auer, K. Saenko, P. Staar, R. Feris, L. Karlinsky\*, "FETA: Towards Specializing Foundation Models for Expert Task Applications", NeurIPS 2022 pdf
- S. Harary\*, **E. Schwartz**\*, A. Arbelle, P. Staar, S. Abu-Hussein, E. Amrani, R. Herzig, A. Alfassy, R. Giryes, H. Kuehne, D. Katabi, K. Saenko, R. Feris, L. Karlinsky\*, "*Unsupervised Domain Generalization by Learning a Bridge Across Domains*", CVPR 2022 (Oral) <u>pdf</u>
- **E. Schwartz\***, L. Karlinsky\*, R. Feris, R. Giryes and A. Bronstein, "Baby steps towards few-shot learning with multiple semantics", Pattern Recognition Letters 2022 pdf
- A. Arbelle\*, S. Doveh\*, A. Alfassy\*, J. Shtok, G. Lev, **E. Schwartz**, H. Kuehne, H. Barak Levi, P. Sattigeri, R. Panda, C. Chen, A. Bronstein, K. Saenko, S. Ullman, R. Giryes, R. Feris, L. Karlinsky, "*Detector-Free Weakly Supervised Grounding by Separation*", ICCV 2021 (Oral) <u>pdf</u>
- C. Baskin\*, N. Liss\*, T.Rozen\*, Y. Chai, E. Zheltonozhskii, **E. Schwartz**, R. Giryes, A. Mendelson and A. M. Bronstein, "*NICE: Noise Injection and Clamping Estimation for Neural Network Quantization*", Mathematics 2021 pdf
- G. Bukchin, **E. Schwartz**, K. Saenko, O. Shahar, R. Feris, R. Giryes\*, L. Karlinsky\* "Fine-grained Angular Contrastive Learning with Coarse Labels", CVPR 2021 (Oral, 3.5% acceptance rate) pdf
- S. Doveh\*, **E. Schwartz**\*, C. Xue, R. Feris, A. Bronstein, R. Giryes, L. Karlinsky "*MetAdapt: Meta-Learned Task-Adaptive Architecture for Few-Shot Classification*", Pattern Recognition Letters 2021 <u>pdf</u>
- L. Karlinsky\*, J. Shtok\*, A. Alfassy\*, M. Lichtenstein\*, S. Harary, **E. Schwartz**, S. Doveh, P. Sattigeri, R. Feris, A. Bronstein, R. Giryes, "StarNet: towards weakly supervised few-shot detection and explainable few-shot classification", AAAI 2021 pdf
- C. Baskin\*, **E. Schwartz**\*, E. Zheltonozhskii, N. Liss, R. Giryes, A. M. Bronstein and A. Mendelson, "UNIQ: Uniform Noise Injection for the Quantization of Neural Networks", ACM Transactions on Computer Systems, 2020 pdf
- N. Diamant\*, D. Zadok\*, C. Baskin, **E. Schwartz** and A. M. Bronstein, "Beholder-GAN: Generation and Beautification of Facial Images with Conditioning on Their Beauty Level", ICIP 2019 pdf
- L. Karlinsky\*, J. Shtok\*, S. Harary\*, **E. Schwartz\***, M. Marder, S. Pankanti, R. Feris, A. Kumar, R. Giryes and A. Bronstein, "*RepMet: Representative-based metric learning for classification and one-shot object detection*", CVPR 2019 pdf
- **E. Schwartz\***, L. Karlinsky\*, J. Shtok, S. Harary, M. Marder, R. Feris, A. Kumar, R. Giryes and A. Bronstein, "*Delta-encoder: an effective sample synthesis method for few-shot object recognition*", NeurIPS 2018 (Spotlight, 3% acceptance rate) pdf
- **E. Schwartz**, R. Giryes and A. M. Bronstein, "*DeepISP: Learning End-to-End Image Processing Pipeline*", IEEE Transactions on Image Processing, 2018 pdf

### **Preprints**

- N. Shabtay\*, E. Schwartz\*, R. Giryes, "Positional-Encoding Image Prior", 2022 pdf
- **E. Schwartz**, A. Arbelle, L. Karlinsky, S. Harary, F. Scheidegger, S. Doveh, R. Giryes, "MAEDAY: MAE for few and zero shot Anomaly-Detection", 2022 pdf

## **Patents**

- E. Schwartz, L. Karlinsky, R. Feris, "System and method for augmenting few-shot object classification with semantic information from multiple sources." US Patent 11,263,488.
- E. Schwartz, L. Karlinsky, S. Doveh, "Task-Adaptive Architecture for Few-Shot Classification." US patent application No. 17/106114.
- O. K. Fabian, G. Adler, L. Y. Chertkow, E. Schwartz, R. Danon, J. Nes-El, "Automated Tattooing System and Method." WO/2020/178818
- L. Karlinsky, J. Shtok, E. Schwartz, "TAFSSL: Task Adaptive Feature Sub-Space Learning for few-shot learning." US patent application No. 17/000,319.
- L. Karlinsky, E. Schwartz, J. Shtok, M. Marder and S. Harary, "Representative-Based Metric Learning for Classification and Few-Shot Object Detection." US patent application No. 16/240,927.
- L. Karlinsky, M. Marder, E. Schwartz, J. Shtok and S. Harary, "Out-of-sample generating few-shot classification networks." US patent application No. 16/206,528.
- C. Baskin, E. Schwartz, E. Zheltonozhskii, N. Liss, R. Giryes, A. M. Bronstein and A. Mendelson, "System and method for emulating quantization noise for a neural network." US provisional patent application No. 62/661,016.
- E. Schwartz, R. Giryes and A. M. Bronstein, "Method and system for end-to-end image processing." U.S. Patent Application No. 16/251,123.
- E. Shalev, S. Katz, and E. Schwartz. "*Imaging devices and methods for authenticating a user*." U.S. Patent Application No. 14/995,025.

# Community Service

- Program Chair Multimodal Foundation Models Workshop, CVPR 2024
- Program Chair Multimodal Foundation Models Workshop, ICCV 2023
- Program Chair Learning with Limited Labels Workshop, CVPR 2020
- Reviewer:
  - o IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI)
  - o Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)
  - O Computer Vision and Image Understanding (CVIU)
  - o International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)
  - o IEEE Transactions on Multimedia
  - o IEEE Transactions on Image Processing